<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>com.notesnook.Notesnook</id>
  <name>Notesnook</name>
  <summary>
    A fully open source &amp; end-to-end encrypted note taking alternative to
    Evernote
  </summary>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-3.0-or-later</project_license>
  <developer_name>Streetwriters</developer_name>
  <description>
    <p>
      Notesnook is a free (as in speech) &amp; open source note taking app
      focused on user privacy &amp; ease of use. To ensure zero knowledge
      principles, Notesnook encrypts everything on your device using
      XChaCha20-Poly1305 &amp; Argon2.
    </p>
    <p>
      Notesnook is our proof that privacy does not (always) have to come at the
      cost of convenience. Our goal is to provide users peace of mind &amp; 100%
      confidence that their notes are safe and secure. Our decision to go fully
      open source is one of the most crucial steps towards that.
    </p>
    <p>
      Notesnook is a user focused note taking tool meant to offer a fully
      end-to-end encrypted note taking experience for everyone. This includes
      the majority of our less tech savy users who just want to take notes
      without all the hassle.
    </p>
    <p>
      In short, Notesnook aims to offer a complete replacement for other
      insecure note taking tools like Evernote &amp; Notion. Because let's be
      honest, these tools offer great productivity but at a great cost to your
      privacy.
    </p>
  </description>
  <url type="homepage">https://notesnook.com/</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/streetwriters/notesnook/issues</url>
  <url type="help">https://docs.notesnook.com/</url>
  <url type="donation">https://opencollective.com/notesnook</url>
  <url type="contribute">https://github.com/streetwriters/notesnook/blob/master/CONTRIBUTING.md</url>
  <launchable type="desktop-id">com.notesnook.Notesnook.desktop</launchable>
  <provides>
    <binary>notesnook</binary>
  </provides>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://notesnook.com/screenshots/desktop/1.jpg</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://notesnook.com/screenshots/desktop/2.jpg</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <categories>
    <category>Education</category>
    <category>Office</category>
  </categories>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>notepad</keyword>
    <keyword>note taking app</keyword>
    <keyword>note taking</keyword>
    <keyword>end-to-end encrypted</keyword>
    <keyword>notebook</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.0">
    <content_attribute id="social-contacts">intense</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="money-purchasing">intense</content_attribute>
  </content_rating>
  <supports>
    <internet>offline-only</internet>
  </supports>
  <releases>
    <release version="2.6.1" date="2023-08-09" urgency="high" type="stable">
      <url type="details">https://github.com/streetwriters/notesnook/releases/tag/v2.6.1</url>
      <description>
        <p>Features &amp; new stuff</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Custom themes</li>
          <li>Much imporved copy/pasting</li>
          <li>Syntax highlighting and rendered math in PDF/HTML exports</li>
          <li>Much more reliable upload of attachments</li>
          <li>Show keyboard shortcuts for editor tools where possible</li>
          <li>Add support for copying link &amp; link text in directly from the Link toolbar in the editor</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Fixes &amp; improvements</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fixed issue where entering Monograph password closed the Publish dialog</li>
          <li>Copy button on code blocks will no longer be disabled in readonly mode</li>
          <li>Fixed color picker height when the editor toolbar is at the bottom</li>
          <li>Pressing the &quot;Tab&quot; key in the Title will now move the focus to the editor</li>
          <li>Respect empty paragraph lines when printing or exporting to PDF/HTML</li>
          <li>Don&#39;t show &quot;Failed to unlock vault&quot; error when exporting a single unlocked note</li>
          <li>All input fields now follow the current color scheme</li>
          <li>Prevent unintentional saving when opening a note</li>
          <li>Respect text direction when adding blocks like heading, lists etc.</li>
          <li>Fix &quot;Dynamic module import is disabled&quot; error when logging in on Firefox ESR &amp; Tor Browser</li>
          <li>Prevent scroll jump &amp; selection loss when toggling focus mode</li>
          <li>Fixed issue where caret would keep jumping to the end when making edits in the sticky editor title</li>
          <li>Overhaul the logger implementation to be less IO intensive</li>
          <li>Fix spell checker on desktop app</li>
          <li>Fixed issue where embeds would not render in readonly mode</li>
          <li>Format time &amp; date on reminders according to the format specified in the Settings</li>
          <li>bring app to front if user tries to start a new instance of Notesnook</li>
          <li>Show progress when restoring large encrypted backups</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
</component>