<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>com.notesnook.Notesnook</id>
  <name>Notesnook</name>
  <summary>
    A fully open source &amp; end-to-end encrypted note taking alternative to
    Evernote
  </summary>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-3.0-or-later</project_license>
  <developer_name>Streetwriters</developer_name>
  <description>
    <p>
      Notesnook is a free (as in speech) &amp; open source note taking app
      focused on user privacy &amp; ease of use. To ensure zero knowledge
      principles, Notesnook encrypts everything on your device using
      XChaCha20-Poly1305 &amp; Argon2.
    </p>
    <p>
      Notesnook is our proof that privacy does not (always) have to come at the
      cost of convenience. Our goal is to provide users peace of mind &amp; 100%
      confidence that their notes are safe and secure. Our decision to go fully
      open source is one of the most crucial steps towards that.
    </p>
    <p>
      Notesnook is a user focused note taking tool meant to offer a fully
      end-to-end encrypted note taking experience for everyone. This includes
      the majority of our less tech savy users who just want to take notes
      without all the hassle.
    </p>
    <p>
      In short, Notesnook aims to offer a complete replacement for other
      insecure note taking tools like Evernote &amp; Notion. Because let's be
      honest, these tools offer great productivity but at a great cost to your
      privacy.
    </p>
  </description>
  <url type="homepage">https://notesnook.com/</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/streetwriters/notesnook/issues</url>
  <url type="help">https://docs.notesnook.com/</url>
  <url type="donation">https://opencollective.com/notesnook</url>
  <url type="contribute">https://github.com/streetwriters/notesnook/blob/master/CONTRIBUTING.md</url>
  <launchable type="desktop-id">com.notesnook.Notesnook.desktop</launchable>
  <provides>
    <binary>notesnook</binary>
  </provides>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://notesnook.com/screenshots/desktop/1.jpg</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://notesnook.com/screenshots/desktop/2.jpg</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <categories>
    <category>Education</category>
    <category>Office</category>
  </categories>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>notepad</keyword>
    <keyword>note taking app</keyword>
    <keyword>note taking</keyword>
    <keyword>end-to-end encrypted</keyword>
    <keyword>notebook</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.0">
    <content_attribute id="social-contacts">intense</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="money-purchasing">intense</content_attribute>
  </content_rating>
  <supports>
    <internet>offline-only</internet>
  </supports>
  <releases>
    <release version="2.4.5" date="2023-03-22" urgency="medium" type="stable">
      <url type="details">https://github.com/streetwriters/notesnook/releases/tag/v2.4.5</url>
      <description>
        <p>Features &amp; new stuff</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Topics are now optional</li>
          <li>Customizable trash cleanup interval</li>
          <li>Tab/window title will now change based on the opened note</li>
          <li>Arm64 support for Windows &amp; Linux </li>
          <li>Images are now much more stable</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Fixes &amp; improvements</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fix autocomplete text color for all text inputs</li>
          <li>Move cell properties button outside of table settings </li>
          <li>Do a healthcheck before logging out user on session revoke </li>
          <li>Fix issue where table options are not visible on some tables </li>
          <li>Fix issue where dropdown required 2 clicks to open in editor toolbar </li>
          <li>Simplify subscription cancellation </li>
          <li>Fix monographs and reminders search</li>
          <li>Keep marks when creating new list items in editor </li>
          <li>Fix sub checklists not getting sorted </li>
          <li>Attachments now automatically infer an extension based on mime type</li>
          <li>App version can now be copied on clicking the version item in settings</li>
          <li>A lot of improvements to code blocks:<ul>
              <li>Pasting from VSCode, GitHub, GitLab, MDN, Stackoverflow etc. will now
                automatically detect &amp; highlight the code blocks</li>
              <li>Typing inside a code block should now be much, much faster</li>
              <li>Wrapping has been disabled for all lines in the code block</li>
            </ul>
          </li>
          <li>Many, many fixes to images:<ul>
              <li>Fix pasting of images from around another web page</li>
              <li>Improve save performance of notes that have a lot of images in them</li>
              <li>Improve image loading animation (there should be much less jank)</li>
              <li>Fix sizing issues of images (and their placeholders) especially on small devices</li>
              <li>All Notesnook clients now only load newly added images on realtime sync instead of
            loading all the images. This greatly speeds up sync.</li>
            </ul>
          </li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>

    <release version="2.4.4" date="2023-02-28" urgency="medium" type="stable">
      <url type="details">https://github.com/streetwriters/notesnook/releases/tag/v2.4.4</url>
      <description>
        <p>Features &amp; new stuff</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Sortable task lists</li>
          <li>Faster editor performance</li>
          <li>New outline lists</li>
          <li>Much smoother app startup experience</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Fixes &amp; improvements</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fix issue where links were editable even in readonly mode</li>
          <li>Fix vertical spacing between nested list items</li>
          <li>Fix issue where Notebooks submenu is positioned incorrectly at the top</li>
          <li>Editor performance improvements</li>
          <li>Fix issue where extra whitespaces/tabs are not preserved in editor</li>
          <li>Adjust horizontal rule&#39;s vertical spacing</li>
          <li>Fix link colors in link hover popup</li>
          <li>Fix issue where Enter key does not move cursor to newly created line on some keyboards
            in Android</li>
          <li>Hide status bar in tablet mode</li>
          <li>Fix issue where note context menu crashed due to incorrect topic references</li>
          <li>Improve backspace handling with lists</li>
          <li>Properly handle duplicate titled notes in bulk note exports</li>
          <li>Hide backup reminder after backup has been downloaded</li>
          <li>Fix issue where attached images wouldn&#39;t load after real time sync</li>
          <li>Improve &quot;Clear completed tasks&quot; performance</li>
          <li>Fix link popup not opening on link focus in mobile</li>
          <li>Attachments can now be multi selected again in the &quot;Manage attachments&quot;
            dialog</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>

  </releases>
</component>